翻译   草草
时间轴   萌
时间轴   Kallen
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
校对   草草
总监   草草
纸牌屋
第五季  第一集
对马斯特森的搜寻仍在继续
国内恐怖分子在逃
总统肖像被焚烧
中东对总统做出反应
爆发反安德伍德抗议
海外退伍军人协会
国家安全局
梅莉莎·米勒:"
你杀了我父亲"
总统请求国会宣战
弗吉尼亚州边境大规模警方行动
马斯特森疑似在该区域
我们都是
吉姆·米勒
要牺牲多少
结束恐惧
为我们的自由而战
我一直想跟你谈谈
I've been meaning to talk with you.
真可怕  不是吗
It's terrifying, isn't it?
总统和我有一个简单的请求
The president and I have a simple request.
告诉我们你看到了什么
Tell us what you see.
如果你周围有任何东西
If anything in your environment
让你觉得奇怪  不对劲
strikes you as a bit odd, a bit off,
拿起电话
pick up the phone.
不管是个包裹  还是不太对劲的人
Whether it's a package or a person that seems out of place,
我们希望你通知我们
we'd love you to let us know.
因为如今外面有很多杂音
Because there's a lot of noise out there these days.
媒体叽叽喳喳  沉湎于过去
A noisy press that's choosing to dwell on the past
却不关注当下的事
instead of what's happening right now.
我丈夫和我想保护你
My husband and I want to protect you.
两周后  你们将前往投票箱
In two weeks' time, you will be heading to the ballot box
决定你们要生活在怎样的国家里
to decide what kind of country you want to live in.
这个选择影响深远
It's a profound choice.
但不管谁赢得选举
But no matter who wins this election,
我们得通力合作
we're going to need to work together,
互相照应
watch out for each other,
是的  也互相监督
and, yes, watch each other,
以确保所有人的安全
to keep us all safe and sound.
告诉我们你看到了什么
Tell us what you see.
我叫克莱尔·安德伍德  我认可这则信息
My name is Claire Underwood, and I approve this message.
我们要再拍一条吗
Should we do one more?
民主党来了吗
Did the Democrats show?
他们没让人失望  几乎都来了  先生
They didn't disappoint. Almost every member, sir.
-几乎  -我列了到场名单
- Almost. - I have a list of those who did.
各位国会议员  我不需要《华盛顿先驱报》
My fellow congressmen, I do not need the Washington Herald
告诉我白宫里住了个恶棍
to tell me that a scoundrel lives in the White House.
我看到民主党来了
I can see the Democrats are here.
他们急着辩论
They're eager to debate.
我对过道另一边的先生们说
I say to the gentlemen on the other side of the aisle...
谢谢
thank you.
我们是否该调查总统
Should we investigate the president
在就任副总统期间犯下的罪行
for crimes committed while he was vice president?
我说  好  我们辩论吧
I say, yes. Let's debate.
我们整日整夜地辩论这恶棍
Let's debate this miscreant all day and all night.
议长女士  议事询问
Madam Speaker. Parliamentary inquiry.
佐治亚州的议员
The gentleman from Georgia
请提出他的议事询问
may state the nature of his parliamentary inquiry.
难道按众议院规则
Do the rules of the House not require
总统不是该受到正式邀请才能出席吗
the president be formally invited in order to attend?
议长女士  容我说一句
Madam Speaker, if I may...
议长有请南卡罗莱纳州议员说话
The Speaker recognizes the gentleman from South Carolina.
总统今天戴了他的国会胸针
The president is wearing his congressional pin today
所以他可以出席一切会议
and is thereby welcome to any and all proceedings.
议长女士  议长女士
Madam Speaker! Madam Speaker!
按众议院规则
Rules of the House state
前众议院成员若与议题
that former members are not allowed on the floor
有直接关系则不得参与辩论
when they have interest in the matter under debate.
议长女士
Madam Speaker,
总统对今天的议题
the president has no interest
既无关联  也无意见
or opinion on the matter being debated today.
众议院安静  众议院安静
The House suspend. The House will suspend.
议长女士  我还在讲话
Madam Speaker, I still do have the floor,
而且我难以相信
and I find it hard to believe
总统对议题无话可说
the president wouldn't have an opinion on the matter being discussed.
如果佛罗里达州议员
If the good gentleman from Florida
肯让出点时间
would yield a portion of his time,
他的疑问肯定能得到解答
I assure him it will satisfy his query.
我给党领袖三分钟时间
I yield three minutes to the leader.
我把我的时间让给前南卡罗莱纳州议员
And I yield my time to the former congressman from South Carolina
现美国总统
and the President of the United States.
议事程序  议事询问
Point of order! Parliamentary inquiry!
议事询问
Parliamentary inquiry!
总统先生  这太不寻常了
Mr. President. This is beyond the norm.
我不在乎
I don't care.
而且我也不在乎
And I also do not care
你们的调查委员会
about your investigative committees.
不  那不是我今天关心的东西
No, that is not what I care about today.
众议院安静
The House will cease.
那不是我今天关心的东西
That is not what I care about today.
我要去出席
I am on my way
一个美国爱国者的葬礼
to the funeral of an American patriot.
一个好人  一个丈夫
A good man, a husband...
一个父亲
a father...
在美国境内被人砍头
who was beheaded on American soil.
众议院
And this chamber
却在今天辩论我
chooses to debate me?
-众议院安静  -我要求
- The House will suspend. - I asked to speak
向众议院发表讲话  却遭到拒绝
to a full session of this chamber and my requests were denied.
-议长女士  -总统先生  你必须让出说话权
- Madam Speaker! - Mr. President, you must yield the floor.
我不会退让的  议长女士
I will not yield, Madam Speaker.
因为我等不了
Because I cannot wait.
其中一个杀人犯
One of the murderers...
杀害了吉姆·米勒先生的一个杀人犯
One of the murderers who killed Mr. Jim Miller...
还逍遥法外
is still out there.
正在逃逸
At large.
你们还要多少证据
How much more proof do you people need?
我要求所有众议院议员表明立场
I demand that every member of this House take a stand.
就像曾经的罗斯福  再之前的威尔逊
Like FDR before, and Wilson before him.
我要求国会
I demand that this Congress
正式对哈里发国宣战
declare a formal declaration of war against ICO,
在本土  也在海外
both here and abroad.
动议休会
Motion to adjourn.
-支持  -众议院休会
- Second! - The House will adjourn.
-总统请停止讲话  -我不会停止
- The president will cease. - I will not cease!
我绝不停止
I will never cease.
我要求国会宣布美利坚合众国
I demand that this Congress declare a state of war
已经并且正在
has existed and does exist
与哈里发国交战
between ICO and the United States of America.
我要求所有众议院成员留在这里
And I demand that every member of this House stay in this chamber
不管要多久
for as long as it takes,
直到你们对我的要求作出表决
until you bring my request to a vote.
否则你们将被历史
Or you will all go down in history
铭记为懦夫
as cowards!
懦夫
Cowards!
请警卫官带走总统
The sergeant at arms will remove the president.
议长女士  我重复  我要求投票
Madam Speaker, I repeat. I demand a vote.
我不会退让
I will not yield.
据称的恐怖分子扎克瑞·霍松被联调局击毙
Alleged terrorist Zachary Hawthorne was killed by the FBI,
但约书亚·马斯特森仍在逃
but Joshua Masterson is still at large.
米勒一家哀悼之时
While the Miller family mourns,
对逃跑的恐怖分子的搜寻仍在继续
the hunt for the missing terrorist continues
气氛十分紧张
and tensions are running high.
总统虽然提出战争
The president may be asking for war,
但看来他已经遭遇了战争
but it seems war's already been declared on him.
我的粉丝
My fans.
联调局正在调查查塔努加市的一起连环枪击案
FBI is looking into a multiple shooting in Chattanooga.
-据报称是与黑帮有关  -不行
- Reports have it gang related. - No.
西弗吉尼亚州一架私人飞机坠毁  机械故障
A private plane went down in West Virginia. Mechanical failure.
佐治亚州多处房屋失火
A series of homes were set on fire in Georgia,
很可能是纵火
most likely arson.
北卡罗来纳州一家便利店
Convenience store in North Carolina
今晨4点左右爆炸
exploded at about 4:00 in the morning.
-商店在哪  -罗利郊外
- Where's the store? - Uh, suburb outside of Raleigh.
起因仍在调查
The cause is still under investigation.
-我去露个脸  -是  夫人
- I'll make an appearance. - Yes, ma'am.
加在日程里  让媒体有时间出动
Just put it on the schedule so the media has time to mobilize.
是  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
总统对约书亚·马斯特森宣战了吧
I take it the president has declared war on Joshua Masterson.
他就不该不让我继续参加通话
He never should've kicked me off that call.
但今天早晨的重点不是政治
But this morning isn't about politics.
是啊
That's right.
我们得对生者表示同情
We need to show some compassion for the living.
对死者表示尊重
And respect for the dead.
他们一家答应了短暂见面
The family's agreed to a moment.
没有媒体  不做讲话  但我们应该能做点什么
No press, no speeches, but we should be able to pull something.
-总统先生  -州长
- Mr. President. - Governor.
他们不知道我们已经为他们做了什么吗
Do they not realize what we've done for them already?
这我说了  先生  但是
I pointed that out, sir, but...
他们家的女儿服了药  目前很脆弱
the daughter's medicated and very fragile at the moment.
好吧
All right.
米勒太太
Mrs. Miller.
-我非常遗憾  -谢谢
- I'm so very sorry. - Thank you.
我保证
And I promise you,
我绝不会罢休
I will not stop
除非所有导致了这场惨剧的人
until everyone responsible for this terrible tragedy
都受到裁决
is brought to justice.
我发誓  上帝为证
And I swear to you, as God is my witness...
再不会有人伤害你和你的家人了
no one will ever harm you or your family ever again.
举国与你和你女儿同哀  米勒太太
The nation mourns with you and your daughter, Mrs. Miller.
-谢谢  如果你不介意  -当然
- Thank you. If you don't mind... - Of course.
总统先生
Mr. President.
我就来
I'll be right along.
你今天很忙  先生
It's a busy day for you today, sir.
今天很悲伤
It's a sad, sad day.
很遗憾结果是这样
It's a shame things didn't turn out differently.
是啊  有些事比我们俩重要  威尔
Yes. Well, some things are bigger than the two of us, Will.
我不希望他在场
I don't want him here!
冷静  梅莉莎  求你
Calm down, Melissa. Please.
都怪他  他死了
It's his fault. He's dead.
-爸爸死了  他杀了他  -求你
- Daddy's dead. He killed him. - Please.
给我点时间
Give me a minute.
-你吃药了吗  -吃了  好吗
- Did you take your medicine? - Yes. Okay?
吃了  吃了
Yes. Yes!
在今天这样的日子  你会去想  该说什么
You do. You think about what you would say on a day like today.
如果今天这样的日子出现
If a day like today were to happen.
但你会让它过去
But you let it pass...
因为你知道  你未来还有漫长的人生
because you know you have so much more left ahead of you.
有很多事可以一起做
So much to do together.
你会想  你想40分钟
You think... You think 40 minutes...
如果我们迟了40分钟
If we were late 40 minutes...
或是两分钟  哪怕一分钟
Or two, or one...
或是我们当时去了别处吃饭
Or if we went somewhere else to eat...
但沉湎过去  活在假设里
But to dwell in the past, to live in what-ifs...
那不是我丈夫的为人
That wasn't my husband.
那不是我们
That wasn't us...
-亲爱的  -求你
- Honey... - Please.
好  来吧
Okay. Come on.
我得
I need to...
我想说说我父亲
I wanted to say about my father...
他是那么坚强  那么勇敢
He was so strong... so brave.
我父亲本打算带我们去
My father was taking us to...
我父亲
My father...
-没事  宝贝  没事的  -我父亲
- Come on, baby. It's okay. - My father...
你杀了我父亲  他是因为你才死的
You killed my father. You're the reason he died.
梅莉莎
Melissa...
没事的  梅莉莎  我们理解
It's all right, Melissa. We understand.
我希望你死  而她当上总统
I hope you die and she becomes president.
那女孩对你说了什么
What did the girl say to you?
她说她希望我死  而你当上总统
She said she hopes I die and that you become the president.
麦卡伦先生  我是国安局副局长迈克尔斯
Mr. Macallan, this is Deputy Director Michaels from the NSA.
我就在你办公室  我们安排了会面
I'm literally in your office. I believe we had a meeting.
从北到南已经展开了大范围搜索
There's been raids as far up as New York and down to the panhandle.
到目前为止
As of now,
格林主要在搜索
Green's focusing in on the
弗吉尼亚和北卡罗来纳的交界处
border between Virginia and North Carolina.
赛斯为今天下午的事准备好了声明
Seth has a statement ready for this afternoon.
不  最好的声明就是不做声明
No. The best statement is no statement.
再说  我们准备好前
Besides, I want Claire to be the voice on this
我要克莱尔来就此事发声
until we're ready.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
-外面人好多  -我们最好先让博奇进来
- Quite a crowd out there. - Well, we better bring Birch in first.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
博奇议员
Congressman Birch.
鲍勃
Bob.
今早的事能载入史册了  是吧
Well, that was a little bit of history this morning, wasn't it?
-可不是呢  -我看不出有别的办法
- It certainly was. - I couldn't see it any other way.
我也同意
No disagreement from here.
你了解共和党的
Well, you know how the Republicans are.
优柔寡断
Anything but a decision.
他们错把抱怨当做了领导
They mistake complaint for leadership.
现在没有调查你的委员会了
Well, instead of a committee to investigate you,
而是成立了讨论宣战的委员会
you got one to discuss your declaration.
直到选举日
All the way to election day.
哪怕有那么一小撮
Even if there's only a handful
有勇气和决心敢抵抗的共和党人
of Republicans with the grit and spit to put up a fight,
我们都能控制舆论
we can control the conversation.
让他们谈什么都好  就是别谈那篇文章
Get them talking about anything but that goddamn article.
好了  我们这边
All right. Now, who from our side
-得去安抚谁  -乌麦克
- do we need to massage? - Womack.
那声明让他措手不及  得让他别掺和
The declaration caught him off guard. Had to keep him out of it.
是他的选民真要去打仗
It's his constituents that actually fight the damn thing.
请尊敬的密苏里州议员进来吧
Well, let's call in the honorable gentleman from Missouri.
-他喜欢波本吧  -是的
- Oh, he's a bourbon man, isn't he? - Yes, he is.
噱头  是的  我说这是噱头
A stunt. Yes, I'm calling it a stunt.
查理  容我说
Charlie, if I may...
汤姆  请说说  你什么意思
Tom, please, what are you implying?
这宣战请求不过又是在分散注意力
This request for a declaration of war is yet another distraction.
我从未像今天这样为总统自豪
And I've never been prouder of the president than I am today.
我不是在否认米勒一家的遭遇  那是个惨剧
I'm not denying what happened to the Millers. It was a tragedy.
不  你在否认  否认它就是惨剧
No, but you are. Because denying it is the tragedy.
这是个规律
This is a pattern.
你丈夫的政府  安德伍德夫人
Your husband's administration, Mrs. Underwood,
-继续在暗箱操作  -汤姆
- continues to operate in the shadows. - Tom...
我知道你相信你的文章很重要
I understand you believe in the importance of your article.
我答应今天来跟你谈谈它
And I agreed to come here today and talk with you about it.
但我们正在奋力保护国家的安全
But we're fighting to keep this country safe.
安德伍德夫人
Mrs. Underwood,
白宫尚未发表任何关于
the White House has yet to release one piece of information
抓捕那些国内恐怖分子的情况
about the attempted capture of those domestic terrorists.
哈里发国恐怖分子  是的
ICO terrorists, yes.
据几小时前的报告称
Reports from a few hours ago
是在北卡罗来纳或弗吉尼亚州
are saying North Carolina or Virginia.
但目前也只有这些
But that's all we have.
我们在慢慢收紧包围圈
Well, we are circling in, we're getting closer.
我告诉你
I will tell you,
我们的情报部门  是真正的英雄
our intelligence community, they are the real heroes.
查理  请回到我的点上  我的消息源确认
Charlie, if we could get back to my point, my sources confirmed--
汤姆
Tom.
海瑟·邓巴  她不是我或我丈夫的朋友
Heather Dunbar, no friend of mine or my husband's,
调查过这些指控  但宣布总统无罪
looked into these charges, and cleared the president.
无罪  得了吧
Cleared? Please.
白宫自《先驱报》刊登了我的文章
The White House has not had a single press briefing
就没举行过一次新闻发布会
since the Herald ran my article.
你总说白宫不就此事发言
You keep saying the White House isn't speaking about this.
但我正坐在这里跟你说话
I am sitting right here talking to you.
不是雷米·丹顿或杰姬·夏普
Not Remy Danton or Jackie Sharp.
也不是卢卡斯·古德温
Or Lucas Goodwin, either.
-什么  -什么意思  卢卡斯·古德温
- What? - Excuse me. Lucas Goodwin, meaning?
我是说  我  我在这儿
I'm saying, me. I'm here.
我不知道这些话我们还要说多少遍
And I don't know how many more times we have to go over this.
汤姆·汉默施密特的文章以前
You know, a Tom Hammerschmidt article used to be
是我打开《华盛顿先驱报》后
the first thing I would look for
第一个要找的东西
when I opened the Washington Herald.
安德伍德夫妇停止了竞选宣传
The Underwoods are no longer campaigning.
他们想怎么说怎么说
They can call it what they want.
如果你想想过去的几天  想想现在的气氛
Well, if you think about the last few days, what's in the air...
或许我们慢慢来
It might not be such a bad idea for us to
也不是坏事
take it one handshake at a time.
或者实话实说
Or call it for what it is.
"国内和国外"
"Home and abroad."
总统基本上在要求许可
The president is essentially asking for permission
在我们的国土上打仗
to fight a war on our soil.
我们不能太强烈反对
We can't push back too hard.
我们不能显得好像对恐怖主义手软
We can't afford to look soft on terror.
我们也不能视而不见
We can't look the other way, either.
你最清楚这样的话会带来的结果
You of all people know where this kind of talk leads.
哈里发国和美利坚合众国
...ICO and the United States of America.
确保处理宣战的委员会
Make sure the committee dealing with the declaration of war
不会进入表决
never gets to a vote.
我们不反对战争  我们反对他的战争
We're not against war, we're against his.
我要你联络议长
And I want you to reach out to the Speaker
查明她要安排谁进入那个委员会
and find out who she's putting on that committee.
我们得回到总统罪行的问题上
We need to get back to the president's crimes.
那才是新闻  唯一的新闻
That's the story. It's the only story.
还有别的吗
Anything else?
我有我的稿子
I have my script.
我不会退让
I will not yield!
我不会
I will not...
哈里
Harry...
我想知道他说了什么  什么时候说的
I want to know what he says and when he says it.
将军可不习惯接受命令
Our general isn't used to taking orders.
威尔  还有
Will, one more thing.
-怎么了  -你妻子
- What? - Your wife.
我知道我们在波利跳上展开了宣传
Okay, I know we opened up this campaign on Pollyhop,
但或许该中止了
but it might be time to close it down...
或至少也该小心点
or at least be more careful.
他们查到了什么
Well, what did they find out?
他们在找的那名
The home of the mother of the terrorist,
恐怖分子的母亲家
you know, the one they're looking for,
昨晚遭人破坏
was vandalized last night.
车库被烧  窗户被打破
Garage set on fire. Broken windows.
汉娜
And, uh, Hannah...
她发了视频
well... she posted.
她在网上维护了那位母亲
She was defending the mother online.
-什么时候  -今天下午
- When? - This afternoon.
这个时机可不妙
The timing is not good on this.
-我给你看  -等会儿的
- I can show you. - Not now.
谢谢
Thank you.
康威州长和我很荣幸能来
Governor Conway and I are honored to be here
陪伴米勒一家和他们的亲友
with the Miller family and their closest friends.
我知道海外退伍军人协会
I know the VFW
是吉姆在诺克斯维尔生活的重要部分
was a big part of Jim's life here in Knoxville.
在国土安全部和我们热线的帮助下
With the help of Homeland and our hotline,
我们认为马斯特森
we think that Masterson
已经进入了弗吉尼亚州的西南角
has crossed into the southwest corner of Virginia.
在斯考特或华盛顿
Scott or Washington.
-然后呢  -然后
- And? - And...
格林助理局长
Assistant Director Green?
我们在依靠空中支援
We're relying on aerial support,
目击和当地执法部门
sightings and local law enforcement.
但我们比较确信
But we're fairly confident
我们可以在接下来24小时内找到他
we can have him pinned down in the next 24 hours.
总统要我们完全确定
The president wants us to be absolutely sure.
我们不能允许他再跑掉了  这事关饭碗
We can't have him getting away again. Careers are at stake.
这桌上的每个人
Everyone around this table
都清楚情况的严重性
is fully aware of the gravity of the situation.
很好  总统知道了会很高兴的
Good. The president will be happy to hear that.
好了  你想要什么样的吻
Okay. What kind of kiss do you want?
-爱斯基摩  -快进
- Eskimo. - In...
快出
and out.
我就回来
I'll be right back.
-你生气了  -是的
- You're angry. - I am.
我被提了问  我回答了
I was asked a question and I answered.
说得太轻了
That's the least of it.
好吧  我现在不想谈这个
Okay, well, I don't want to talk about it right now.
你是想输掉竞选吗  是吗
Are you trying to lose this election? Are you?
威尔  得了
Will, stop it.
你维护的这女人
This woman that you're defending...
她儿子砍了别人的头
Her son just cut someone's head off.
他还逍遥在外
And he's still out there somewhere.
-你知道这看上去什么样吗  -别说了
- Do you understand what this looks like? - Stop it.
你知道我们儿子为什么睡不着吗
Do you want to know why our son can't sleep?
他才八岁  却失眠了
He's eight years old, and he can't sleep.
因为他做恶梦
Because he's having nightmares.
因为他觉得
Because he thinks
酒店里有头黑色大狗在到处跑
there's a big black dog running around the hotel.
-狗  -对
- Dog? - Yes.
他闭上眼睛  就能听到它咆哮
He closes his eyes, and he can hear it growling.
他害怕  威尔
He's scared, Will.
我说那些话是因为那女人也是受害者
I said what I said because that woman is a victim.
我们都是
We all are.
这必须停止了
And it has to stop.
我希望你赢
I want you to win.
去给自己倒一杯酒  我就回来
Get yourself a drink. I'll be right back.
那是他母亲  这是汉娜的回应
That's the mother. And this is Hannah's response.
她不是罪犯
She's not a criminal
不该因为她儿子的罪受惩罚
and should not be punished for the sins of her son.
我知道我们都反对
We all, I know, reject
这两位困惑受伤的青年的说法和行为
the rhetoric and actions of these damaged, troubled young men.
我是说  这是该反省的时候
What I mean is, this is a time for reflection,
而不是进攻
not aggression...
她没有表示宽恕  但表示了同情
So she's not condoning it, but it is sympathetic.
把约书亚和扎克瑞说成
Plays into the idea that Joshua and Zachary
一对儿寻找目标的困惑青年
were just a pair of troubled kids looking for a cause,
跟普通学校枪击手没什么区别
no different than some school shooter.
视频转发超过10万次了
The post has been shared over 100,000 times.
我想跟她谈谈
I want to talk with her.
-汉娜  -那个母亲
- Hannah? - The mother.
我们一直对你在哪露面十分小心
We've been very careful about where you appear.
-莉安  能让我们单独待会儿吗  -当然
- LeAnn, will you excuse us for a moment? - Of course.
我们得加大恐惧感
We need to dial up the terror.
那个母亲能帮我们做到
And the mother can help us with that.
但那样我们还得找到马斯特森
But that also means we have to locate Masterson.
尽快
Soon.
汤姆在等我
Tom is waiting for me.
你去吧
Well, you go on.
弗兰西斯
Francis...
我不该在葬礼上哭
I shouldn't have cried at the funeral.
-不  那效果很好  -对我不好
- No, it played beautifully. - Not for me.
跟我来
Come with me.
来吧  告诉他你要迟点到
Come on. Just tell him you'll be late.
-总统先生  -没事  警官
- Mr. President. - It's all right, Officer.
夫人
Ma'am.
能给我你的目镜吗
May I have your scope?
你枪上的目镜  我保证还回来
Scope on your gun. I promise I'll give it back.
谢谢  过来
Thank you. Come here.
如果你把目镜举在离脸稍远处
Now, if you just hold the scope a little a ways from your face...
往下看  直向下  草坪对面
and look down, straight down, across the lawn...
门那里
right to the gate.
看到他们了吗
You see them?
那些人想要发声  有些是支持的  有些反对
Those people want a voice. Some for, some against.
他们也在草坪那头往这边看
And they're looking back across the lawn,
看这栋房子  这些窗户
toward this house and these windows...
他们在想
and they're thinking,
"不知道总统
"I wonder what the president
和第一夫人今晚在做什么
and the First Lady are doing tonight.
他们能保护我们吗"
And will they be able to protect us?"
我该在场的
I should have been there.
哪里
Where?
你受枪伤时  我真该在场的
When you got shot. I wish I was there.
或许我还能
Maybe I could've...
保护你
protected you.
你瞧  那些人只想
You see, all those people want...
有人保护他们  不用面对可怕的真相
is someone to keep them from what they're afraid to know.
总统和第一夫人今晚要做什么呢  弗兰西斯
And what are the president and First Lady doing tonight, Francis?
托马斯不是还等着你呢吗
Well, I believe Thomas is waiting for you.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
我们明早见
I'll see you in the morning.
你有烟吗
Do you have a smoke?
谢谢
Thank you.
*我知道我的人民今晚在想什么*
*I know what my people are thinking tonight*
BGM: I Wonder What the King Is Doing Tonight
*穿过阴影  他们漫步回家*
*As home through the shadows they wander*
*大家都窃笑着*
*Everyone smiling in secret delight*
*他们看着城堡  思索着*
*As they stare at the castle and ponder*
*当风往这边吹*
*And whenever the wind blows this way*
*你几乎能听到大家说*
*You can almost hear everyone say*
*不知国王今晚在做什么*
*I wonder what the king is doing tonight*
我一直在找你
I've been looking for you.
我饿了
I got hungry.
所以去了主厨房
So I went down to the main kitchen.
下面的人真不错
That's a lovely group of people you have down there.
如果你需要什么  可以叫人拿上来
If there's anything you need, it can be brought up.
我直到吃在嘴里才知道自己需要什么
I didn't know what I needed until I was eating it.
我听到了总统的声明
I heard the president's declaration.
很有力
Very compelling.
你究竟怎么想的
What did you really think?
简直像真的一样
It was almost like the real thing.
国安局的人很厉害  非常厉害
The NSA has good people. Very good.
-太厉害了  -不如你厉害
- Too good. - Not as good as you.
足以找到我的算法了
Good enough to find my algorithms.
那不代表他们知道我们用它做了什么
That doesn't mean they knew what we were using them for.
不不
No, no.
前一秒  他们还叫我回家  然后紧接着
One second, they send me home, and then the next,
他们说  "回来"
they tell me, "Come back!"
他们肯定要监视我了  这是个陷阱
They'll been watching me. This is a trap.
或是唯一的出路
Or the only way out.
该死
God damn it.
-你想要出路吗  -你不想吗
- You want out? - Don't you?
莉安
LeAnn...
我们做了违法的事
we have done some illegal things here.
还有其他竞选
There are other campaigns.
-如果你可以打入国安局  -那不可能
- If you can get into the NSA... - That's not possible.
进入他们的系统  你可以解决的
...into their system, you can fix this.
-你没听我说  -我听了
- You're not listening to me. - I am.
我了解安德伍德夫妇
I know the Underwoods.
我们如果想平安度过
The only way that we are gonna survive this...
就得让他们赢
is if they win.
你可以帮他们赢
You can help them win.
我知道你能
I know you can.
你走后我就加入了报社
I got on the paper right around the time you left.
你从时尚版块起步的吗
Did you start in Style?
都市
Metro desk.
然后我发了篇报道  一个街头时尚
But then I did this piece, a street fashion,
街头的孩子的报道
kids on the street thing.
没想到你会叫我来
I'm surprised you asked for me.
队伍里有些人员变化
Some people are being moved around and off the team.
马斯特森的报道  "战争  有什么好处"
The Masterson story. "War, what is it good for?"
你对调查性新闻感兴趣吗
Were you ever interested in investigative journalism?
要问我  不是这种的就不叫新闻
If you ask me, if it's not investigating, it's not journalism.
听这里的人说  你能让任何人对你开口
Word around here is you can get anybody to talk to you.
过了8点  又有酒的话
After 8:00, with a drink in their hands...
是啊
yeah.
他们说她是个...
She's the one they say you called a...
你懂的
you know.
对不起  我有点紧张
I'm sorry. I'm a little nervous.
你算是传奇人物
You're sort of a legend and...
报道总统的文章
articles on the president?
能跟你合作是莫大的荣幸
It'd be an honor to work with you in any capacity.
能参与进来
To be part of this.
你们找到他了吗
Did you find him? Did you?
再等一下就好
It'll only be another moment.
因为我已经做尽了一切
Because I've done all I can.
你们叫我做的一切  你知道的
Everything you told me to. You know that.
他们知道的  是吧
They know that, don't they?
安德伍德夫人
Mrs. Underwood.
我想跟马斯特森女士说话
I was hoping to speak to Ms. Masterson.
就我们俩
Just the two of us.
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem?
这有点极端
It is a bit extreme.
把禁飞令扩大到这样的范围
Expanding the no-fly list to this extent.
单是对签证的限制就前所未有
The restrictions on visas alone is unprecedented.
我们要如何解释
How do we justify?
白宫顾问已经讨论过了
The White House counsel's been all through that.
都白纸黑字写着了
It's there in black and white.
我们基本上是在
We're virtually closing down our borders
-没有证据的情况下关闭国境  -会有的
- without any hard evidence to back it up. - It's coming.
很多无辜的人正想进入这个国家
A lot of innocent people are trying to get into this country.
他们可能因此受伤害
They could be hurt by this.
如此大的政策变动  我想好好做
A change in policy this big, I want it done right.
我要你让世界知道
I want you to let the world know
如果他们还想继续进入这个国家
that if they want to continue coming to this country
上我们的医院  我们的学校
for our hospitals, our colleges,
我们的高尔夫球场什么的
our golf courses and God knows what else...
他们光是
they're going to have to deliver
把我的脑袋贴在棍子上烧是不够的
more than my head on the end of a burning stick.
听着  凯茜
Now look, Cathy,
我知道你有辛苦经营的人脉
I know you have well-earned relationships out there.
都是老交情
Long-standing.
我没有保留  弗兰西斯  我都联络了
I'm not holding back, Francis. I have reached out.
那我需要你再加把劲
Then I need you to reach further.
我要可行的情报
I want actionable intelligence.
我要知道哈里发国在哪  或者至少
I want to know where ICO is, or at the very least,
所有人都在找他们
that everyone's out there looking.
明白了吗
Are we clear?
明白了
We're clear.
谢谢  凯茜  我知道你不会让我失望
Thank you, Cathy. I know you won't let me down.
他死了
He's dead.
你是来告诉我这个的吗
Is that why you're here?
我们还在找他
We're still looking for him--
因为如果他死了  我要见到他  摸到他
Because if he's dead, I want to see him. To touch him.
-我是想帮忙  -马斯特森太太
- I'm trying to help... - Ms. Masterson,
-但他没有联系我  -求你
- ...but he hasn't contacted me. - please.
我也希望他联系我
I wish he would.
我明白  冷静
I understand. Calm down.
他不像他们说的那样  是个禽兽
He's not a monster like they all say.
我不知何时失去了他  但他不是...
I lost him somewhere. But he's not...
但这世上还是有禽兽的  是吧
But still, monsters do exist, don't they?
我想要律师
I want my lawyer.
为什么
What for?
对不起  我不知道我为什么那么说
I'm sorry, I don't know why I said that.
我已经不知道我都在说什么了
I don't know why I say anything anymore.
我想见你
I wanted to see you...
是想问你一个简单的问题
to ask you a simple question.
你不知道你家里发生的事吗
Didn't you know what was going on in your home?
-什么  -你知道的
- Excuse me? - You knew...
早在他去巴基斯坦之前
even before he went to Pakistan.
-是你养大了他  -不
- I mean, you raised him. - No.
不  他是有问题  他迷失了
No. He had some problems. He got lost.
但不  不是这样的
But no, nothing like this.
但你看到他做了什么吧
But you saw what he did, didn't you?
-不  -你想看吗
- No. - Would you like to see it?
如果你想  我们可以给你看
We can show it to you, if you like.
不  别
No. Please don't.
他对那家人  对那个人做的事
What he did to that family, to that man...
什么样的人能做出这种事
What sort of person would do such a thing?
他是我儿子
He's my son.
天呐
Oh, God.
我知道  很可怕  是吧
I know. It's awful, isn't it?
谢谢
Thank you.
你今天离开时
When you leave today,
会有记者  有摄像机在外面等着
there will be some reporters, some cameramen out there.
但你不需要说太多
But you don't need to say very much.
你只需要叫约书自首
You just need to ask Josh to turn himself in.
这世上还有很多辛辛苦苦的父亲和母亲
There are so many hardworking mothers and fathers out there.
这可能发生在他们任何人身上
This could've happened to any of them.
我们就要抓到你儿子了  马斯特森太太
We are close to capturing your son, Ms. Masterson,
我会尽全力让你见到他
and I will do my best to have you see him.
我想走了
I want to go.
没人不让你走
No one's keeping you.
但她安排了谁
But who did she put in?
议长安排了谁进委员会
Who did the Speaker put on the committee?
大多是席位无忧的长期议员
Mostly lifers, with secure seats.
还剩两周  很难反对战争
We're two weeks out. It's hard to say no to war.
你和我有共同点
You and I have some things in common.
-我们都讨厌总统  -不  我终归是民主党人
- We both dislike the president. - No. I'm still a Democrat.
但是右倾
Who leans to the right.
艾力克斯  你的确是有些右倾的
Alex, you do actually lean a little to the right.
他是三军统帅
Look, he's the commander in chief.
他完全有权力决定去哪打仗
He's got all the authority he needs to fight them where they are.
此时此刻  国内就有个战场
Well, there's one here. Out there, right now, as we speak.
我是很支持美国执法机构的
Well, I'm a big fan of American law enforcement.
他们很快就能找到他
They'll find him soon enough.
我们不能让弗兰西斯·安德伍德让我们国家
We can't just let Francis Underwood turn us into a nation
变得时刻心惊胆战
that's always looking over their shoulder.
如果你能挤进那个委员会
If you can get yourself onto that committee,
我觉得主席会让你充分表达意见的
I got a feeling the Chair will give you all the time you need.
我的司机会送你回车上  但议员先生
My driver will take you back to your car. But, Congressman...
这是你的机会
this is your chance.
我觉得你也知道
And I think you know it.
非常感谢你们来
Thank you so much for coming out here.
Thank you so much for coming out.
见到你们真好  谢谢你们来
Great to see you. Thanks for coming out.
走开
Just go away!
你根本不知道自己家里发生的事
You have no idea what is happening in your own homes.
你知道他在哪吗  马斯特森太太
Have you any idea where he is, Mrs. Masterson?
约书  求你
Josh, please...
求你  求你自首吧
please, please turn yourself in.
这得停下了  不
This has all got to stop. No, no.
在财政部干了10年  他正等着呢
...this after ten years with Treasury, he was waiting for it.
是啊
Yeah...
安德伍德夫人
Mrs. Underwood!
政府是否认为爆炸跟
Does the administration believe that the explosion was connected
-约书亚·马斯特森有关  -我们尚不确定
- with Joshua Masterson somehow? - We're not sure yet.
有很多证据支持这一可能性
Uh, there is strong evidence to suggest.
店主的确是在外国出生
The owner of the establishment was foreign-born.
跟海外的哈里发国有关吗
Any connection to ICO overseas?
我认为助理局长
I think our Deputy Director
克拉克更有资格回答这个问题
Clark here is better equipped to answer that.
我们在调查  但现在  我们设立了热线
We're looking into it. In the meantime, we've set up a hotline.
如果有任何居民
If anyone in the community
-有什么...  -如果共和党候选人
- has any-- - And if the Republican candidate
和余下的共和党人不肯承认
and the rest of his party refuse to acknowledge
国内威胁的严重性
the seriousness of the threat made here at home...
那么我们会的
know that we will.
联调局正在收集言论和照片
The FBI is currently gathering a list of words and images.
如果它们出现在了你的孩子
If they appear on your children's
或你同事的设备上  请务必
or your coworkers' devices, please--
战争婊子
War whore!
-让开  -上车
- Move! - Car!
就是油漆而已  她没事
It was just paint. She's all right.
还有什么  说吧  道格  不会那么糟的
And what else? Spit it out, Doug. It won't taste so bad.
先生  我知道你在这事上跟我看法不同
Sir, I know you disagree with me on this.
但格林局长和他的团队
But Director Green and his team
有了抓捕地点  准备行动了
have a location for the takedown and they're ready to act.
他们确定找对地方了吗
And they're positive it's the right location?
-非常确定  -什么时候
- Adamant. - When?
再过几小时
Hours.
我们可以在战况室协调
We can coordinate out of the Situation Room.
不  我要亲自见他
Oh, no. I'm gonna meet him in person.
先生  我强烈反对
Sir, I strongly advise against that.
知道了  但我要到场
Duly noted, but I'll be on-site.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
人们随时会爆发恐惧  真是不可思议
It's amazing how ready people are to be afraid.
历史会证明他们是对的
History would prove them right.
幸好这个水能洗掉
You're lucky this is coming off with water.
可能会更糟呢
Could've been worse.
有点溅到你耳朵后面了
Some found its way behind your ear.
-我该害怕吗  -别耍聪明
- Should I be afraid? - Don't be smart.
我是该害怕  是吧
I should, shouldn't I?
我从你那儿偷了东西
I stole something from you.
什么
What?
是什么无所谓
What it is, doesn't matter.
我就是想要一样你的东西
I just wanted something that was yours.
放回去
Well, put it back.
瀑布
Waterfalls.
国安局用瀑布标记0day漏洞利用工具
The NSA marked their zero-day exploits as waterfalls.
它们能让我们进入什么
What can they get us into?
我们可以后门进入一些很火的社交网站
We can backdoor into some very popular social media.
我可以把任何你能想到的东西
I can insert anything your imagination can think of
放到那些网站上
into those sites.
安德伍德夫妇或其他人的
Underwoods or otherwise.
多个消息源称
...reports coming in from a variety of sources
当地警方和联调局
stating that local police enforcement and FBI agents
正在前方
are currently on the ground.
我们接到报告称
We're receiving reports that
弗吉尼亚州边境有大量警力
there's a great deal of police activity on the Virginia border.
我们目前不能确认
We cannot confirm at this time,
但我们认为  这跟对国内恐怖分子
but we believe this is connected to the manhunt
约书亚·马斯特森的搜寻有关
for domestic terrorist Joshua Masterson.
约书亚·马斯特森可能很快将被捕
The capture of Joshua Masterson may be close at hand.
联调局仍未就此发表评论
The FBI is still not commenting,
但请看航拍情况
but if you look at this aerial view,
可以看到全副武装的人
you can see heavily-armed men
正在林间穿行
making their way through this wooded area.
长官  他不在这儿
Sir, he's not here.
我们只审出了一些零散的国内联络人
All we have are some loose domestic connections.
对海外哈里发国的变态崇拜
A perverse idolization of ICO overseas.
他不肯证实有大规模的国内网络存在
He refuses to confirm any wide-ranging homegrown network.
我们的审讯官认为此人已无价值
Our interrogators are confident the asset is no longer valuable.
冒险诱供已经不可行了
And risk to reward no longer tenable.
先生  我们已经到达了临界点
Sir, we have reached a breaking point.
你以为我没有已经抓到了他
Did you think I didn't already have him?
我会任他在外面流窜吗
That I would have left him out there somewhere?
我以为你了解我呢
And I thought you knew me.
约书
Josh.
约书亚
Joshua.
你想活吗
Do you want to live?
说出我们想知道的
Tell us what we want.
Tell us what we want to hear.
你不是个殉道者  是吧
You're no martyr, are you?
看看你
Look at you.
不  你不是个殉道者
No, you're not a martyr.
没人会记住你所做的事
No one will remember what you've done,
不管是在这人间  还是在你的天堂
either here on Earth or in your heaven.
你为什么选择米勒一家
So why did you pick the Millers?
为什么
Why?
你看到了什么
What did you see?
是因为那女孩吗
Was it the girl?
你是先看上了她吗
Did you see her first?
你看上了什么
What did you see?
还是她先看到了你
Or did she see you first?
没错  就是这样吧  她看到了你
Yeah, that's it, isn't it? She saw you.
她一眼就看穿了你  是吧
She looked right through you, didn't she?
我不需要再看到他了
I don't need to see this person anymore.
-处理掉他  -先生
- Get rid of the asset. - Sir.
他是个禽兽  但他终归是美国公民
He's an animal, but he's still an American citizen.
我们在交战  他是敌方战斗人员
We are at war. And he is an enemy combatant.
他砍下那可怜人的脑袋时  就失去了一切
And he lost whatever rights he might have had as an American
美国人的权利
when he cut that poor man's head off.
所以少跟我说你的骄傲或立场
So don't give me your pride or your position.
因为如果你当初能照做
Because none of this would have happened
这一切都不会发生了
if you'd done what you were told in the first place.
我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
你当然会  而且会自愿自觉地做
Yes, you will, and you will do so willingly.
我要你拍到杀他时好的
And I want you to get some good, usable footage...
可用的录像
of his killing.
然后销毁其他一切
And then destroy everything else.
我们要发布约书亚·马斯特森被杀的视频
We will be releasing footage of Joshua Masterson's killing.
政府和情报机构
The administration and the intelligence community
本希望活捉他
were hoping to take him alive.
但我想赞扬
But I would like to commend
反恐处助理局长  纳森·格林
Assistant Director of Counterterrorism, Nathan Green.
当然还有
And of course all of the work
国务卿杜兰特做的一切相关幕后工作
that Secretary Durant has done behind the scenes on all of this.
调查目前为止收集到的信息
The information the investigation has gathered so far
表明约书亚·马斯特森和扎克瑞·霍桑
points to Joshua Masterson and Zachary Hawthorne
跟海外的哈里发国
having strong connections to ICO abroad
和国内在发展的哈里发国网络有密切关系
and ICO's growing network domestically.
所以我想直接对哈里发国说以下这些话
And so I would like to say this to ICO directly.
你们再别想左右哪怕一个年轻人的头脑
You will not infect the mind of one more of our young people,
因为我不会罢休  直到我找到你
because I will not stop until I find you.
这话也说给悲痛中的米勒一家
And I say that for the grieving Miller family,
希望他们今晚能睡得着
whom I hope will find some sleep tonight.
我还敦促国会
I also urge Congress
加快进程
to accelerate the process
就我的宣战请求做出表决
and vote on my request for a declaration of war.
-总统先生  -我不会回答问题
- Mr. President? - I will not be answering questions.
接下来赛斯会接手
Seth will take it from here.
不好分辨  但那应该是致命一击
It's hard to see, but I think that was the killshot.
请记住  这些报道尚未经证实
Now, please remember, these reports are unconfirmed
我们还在等待白宫的声明
and we're waiting on a statement from the White House.
我们可以报道  有大量...
What we can report is a great deal...
你为什么看这个
Why are you watching this?
...这片林区  有枪击声  既有...
...this wooded area. And shots being fired, both by and--
喂
Hello?
喂  我是弗兰西斯·安德伍德
Hello. This is Francis Underwood.
是他
It's him.
委员会在找雷米·丹顿和杰姬·夏普
The committee is looking for Remy Danton and Jackie Sharp.
他们跟哈里发国和战争有什么关系
What do either of them have to do with ICO or the war?
国会那边的消息是他们会要你
The talk up on the Hill is they're going to invite you
和你的手下去作证
and the rest of your staff to testify.
他们要利用宣战的事做调查
They're gonna use the Declaration of War to investigate.
是的
That's right.
他们要用弗兰克要求组建的委员会调查他
They're gonna use the committee Frank asked for to investigate him.
-该死  -是啊  道格
- Fuck. - That's right, Doug.
"该死"
"Fuck."
很难理解...
It's difficult to underst--
或许如果你能稍稍平静一点
Well, perhaps if you could just calm down for a moment.
够了
Please stop it.
我以为这消息能给你带来一丝宽慰
I thought this news would bring you some relief.
总统打给了米勒太太
The president called Mrs. Miller.
我向你和你女儿保证过  我会...
I promised you and your daughter that I would--
放过她吧
Leave her alone.
或许我们还是
Well, perhaps we should speak
等你好一些了再谈吧
when you're feeling a little more up to it.
我不想听到你说话  或收到你的任何消息
I don't want to hear you. Or from you.
-你对我们家做的事...  -什么
- What you did to my family... - What?
别把我们扯进去  别用我丈夫的名字
Leave us out of it. And do not use my husband's name.
听我说  太太
Listen, Mrs.--
她挂了
She hung up.
我们去走走吧
Let's go for a walk.
总统先生
Mr. President!
说出他们想听的
Tell them what they need to know.
总统先生
Mr. President!
你们好
Hello.
总统先生  谢谢  谢谢
Mr. President. Thank you, thank you.
你好
Hello.
你们完全不需要害怕
You have nothing to be afraid of.
你完全不需要害怕
"宣战权"在美国法律和政府实践中是一个比较混乱的灰色区域
美国宪法规定国会拥有正式宣战权  但又规定美国总统是三军统帅
作为行政机构的首脑  历史上  美国总统经常援引后一条规定
以自己作为三军统帅有绝对的军事指挥权为由绕过国会  发动军事行动
事实上  二战之后  美国总统发动大规模军事行动时  从未寻求国会授权
为了夺回宣战权  国会1973年通过了《战争权力法案》
但该法案同时规定  总统可以先发动军事行动  后在90天内寻求国会授权
73年的法案通过后  除了大小布什发动两次海湾战争时获得了国会授权
其余绝大多数情况下  美国总统都无视这个法律的存在
所以现实中  "国会授权"反而成了总统想回避军事行动时的一个借口
而真正下决心采取行动时  反而可以不用理会国会